When I opened Mott Hall Bridges Academy in 2010,
عندما افتتحتُ أكاديمية موت هال بريدجز أكاديمي في 2010،
my goal was simple:
هدفي كان بسيطاً:
open a school to close a prison.
افتتح مدرسة لتغلق سجناً.
Now to some, this was an audacious goal,
الآن ،للبعض كان هذا الهدف جريئًا
because our school is located in the Brownsville section of Brooklyn --
لأن موقع مدرستنا يقع في قسم براونزفيل من بروكلين--
one of the most underserved and violent neighborhoods
واحدة من أكثر الأحياء العنيفة و غير المخدومة
in all of New York City.
في كل مدينة نيويورك.
Like many urban schools with high poverty rates,
مثل العديد من المدارس في المُدن، ومع ارتفاع معدلات الفقر،
we face numerous challenges,
نواجه عدداً ضخماً من التحديات،
like finding teachers who can empathize
مثل العثور على معلمين يمكنهم أن يتعاطفوا
with the complexities of a disadvantaged community,
مع تعقيدات مجتمع المحرومين،
lack of funding for technology,
و نقص التمويل من أجل التقنية،
low parental involvement
و تدخلات الأهل المنخفضة،
and neighborhood gangs that recruit children as early as fourth grade.
وعصابات الحي التي تُجند الأطفال في وقت مبكر من الصف الرابع.
So here I was,
إذاً أنا كنت هنا،
the founding principal of a middle school that was a district public school,
المؤسس الرئيسي لمدرسة متوسطة كانت مدرسة عمومية في لمنطقة،
and I only had 45 kids to start.
كان لدي فقط 45 طفلا في البداية
Thirty percent of them had special needs.
30% منهم من ذوي الحتياجات الخاصة.
Eighty-six percent of them were below grade level
86% منهم كانوا دون معدل الصف
in English and in math.
في اللغة الانكليزية وفي الرياضيات.
And 100 percent were living below the poverty level.
و100% يعيشون دون خط الفقر.
If our children are not in our classrooms,
إذا لم يكن أطفالنا في قاعات الدرس،
how will they learn?
كيف لهم أن يتعلموا؟
And if they're not learning,
وإذا لم يتعلموا،
where would they end up?
أين سينتهي بهم الأمر؟
It was evident when I would ask my 13-year-old,
عندما سألت شخصا في سن 13 ، كان الدليل،
"Young man,
"أيها الفتى
where do you see yourself in five years?"
أين ترى نفسك خلال خمس سنوات؟"
And his response:
وكانت إجابته:
"I don't know if I'm gonna live that long."
"لاأعلم إذا كنت سأعيش لذلك الوقت."
Or to have a young woman say to me
أو امرأة شابة تخبرني
that she had a lifelong goal of working in a fast-food restaurant.
بأنه يوجد لديها هدف لمدى الحياة ، بأن تعمل في مطعم وجبات سريعة.
To me, this was unacceptable.
بالنسبة لي، هذا ليس مقبولاً.
It was also evident that they had no idea
وهذا دليل أيضاً بعدم امتلاكهم أدنى فكرة
that there was a landscape of opportunity
بوجود مساحة من الفرص
that existed beyond their neighborhood.
تقع أبعد من حيّهم.
We call our students "scholars," because they're lifelong learners.
إننا ندعوا طلابنا بـ"الباحثين" لأنهم متعلمون لمدى الحياة.
And the skills that they learn today
وهذه المهارات التي يتعلمونها اليوم
will prepare them for college and career readiness.
ستُعدهم للجامعة ، و للاستعداد الوظيفي.
I chose the royal colors of purple and black,
اخترت ألوان ملكية من البنفسجي والأسود،
because I want them to be reminded that they are descendants of greatness,
لأني أريد أن أذكرهم بأنهم أحفاد العظمة،
and that through education,
وهذا عبر التعلم.
they are future engineers,
إنهم مهندسو المستقبل،
scientists,
علماء،
entrepreneurs
رواد أعمال
and even leaders who can and will take over this world.
وحتى قادة يستطيعون قيادة العالم.
To date,
اليوم،
we have had three graduating classes,
لدينا ثلاث دفعات تخرج.
at a 98 --
و98%--
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
At a 98-percent graduation rate.
بمعدل تخرج يبلغ 98% .
This is nearly 200 children,
تقريبا 200 طفل،
who are now going to some of the most competitive high schools
سيذهبون الآن إلى أكثر المدارس الثانوية تنافسية
in New York City.
في مدينة نيويورك.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
It was a cold day in January
كان يوماً باردا في يناير
when my scholar, Vidal Chastanet, met Brandon Stanton,
عندما قابل باحثي فيدال تشاسنيت ،براندون ستانتون.
the founder of the popular blog "Humans of New York."
مؤسس المّدونة المشهورة "أٌناس في نيويورك."
Brandon shared the story of a young man from Brownsville
براندون شارك قصة شاب من برانزفيل
who had witnessed violence firsthand,
الذي شهد العنف بشكل مباشر
by witnessing a man being thrown off of a roof.
بمشاهدة رجل يتم إلقاؤه من على السطح.
Yet he can still be influenced by a principal
ومع هذا مازال بإمكانه أن يتأثر من قِبل مديرة
who had opened up a school that believes in all children.
التي فتحت مدرسة تؤمن بجميع الأطفال.
Vidal embodies the story of so many of our underprivileged children
فيدال يُجسد الكثير من الأطفال المحرومين لدينا
who are struggling to survive,
الذين يعانون ليعيشوا.
which is why we must make education a priority.
لهذا السبب يجب علينا أن نجعل التعليم أولوية.
Brandon's post created a global sensation
المنشور الذي نشره براندون خلق ضجة في العالم
that touched the lives of millions.
لامست حياة الملايين .
This resulted in 1.4 million dollars being raised
نتج عن هذا جمع 1,419,509$
for our scholars to attend field trips to colleges and universities,
لباحثينا ليحضروا رحلات ميدانية لكليات وجامعات،
Summer STEAM programs,
و برامج صيفية للفرق،
as well as college scholarships.
وكذلك منح كليات.
You need to understand
يجب عليكم أن تُدركوا
that when 200 young people from Brownsville visited Harvard,
أنه عندما زار 200 شخص من برانزفيل ،هارفرد
they now understood
فَهِمُوا الآن
that a college of their choice was a real possibility.
بأن جامعة من اختيارهم ،احتمال حقيقي.
And the impossibilities that had been imposed upon them
المستحيلات التي فُرضت عليهم
by a disadvantaged community
من قِبل مجتمع المحرومين
were replaced by hope and purpose.
استُبدلت بالأمل والتصميم.
The revolution in education is happening in our schools,
ثورة التعليم تحدث في مدارسنا.
with adults who provide love,
مع بالغين يأمّنون الحب،
structure,
و النظام،
support
و الدعم،
and knowledge.
والمعرفة.
These are the things that inspire children.
هذه الأشياء التي تُلهم الأطفال.
But it is not an easy task.
ولكن هذه ليست مهمة سهلة.
And there are high demands
هنالك مطالب عدة
within an education system that is not perfect.
داخل نظام تعليمي يعوزه الكثير.
But I have a dynamic group of educators
ولكن لدي مجموعة حيوية من المربين
who collaborate as a team to determine what is the best curriculum.
الذين يتعاونون كفريق ليقرروا أفضل المناهج.
They take time beyond their school day,
إنهم يقضون وقتاً حتى بعد دوامهم المدرسي،
and come in on weekends
ويعملون في العُطل،
and even use their own money to often provide resources
و يستخدمون كذلك مالهم الخاص في بعض الأحيان ليُأمّنوا موارد
when we do not have it.
عندما لا تتوفر لدينا.
And as the principal,
وكمديرة مدرسة،
I have to inspect what I expect.
يجب علي أن أتفقد ما أتوقع.
So I show up in classes
لهذا أحضر الصفوف
and I conduct observations to give feedback,
وأقوّم بالملاحظات لأعطي التغذية الراجعة،
because I want my teachers to be just as successful
لأني أريد لأساتذتي أن يكونوا ناجحين
as the name Mott Hall Bridges Academy.
كما اسم أكاديمية (موت هال بريدجيز).
And I give them access to me every single day,
وأعطي لهم الحق بالوصول إلي في كل يوم،
which is why they all have my personal cell number,
لهذا السبب ،جميعهم لديهم رقم هاتفي الخلوي الخاص،
including my scholars and those who graduated --
بما فيهم باحثون لدي والذين تخرجوا--
which is probably why I get phone calls and text messages
ربما لهذا السبب أتلقى مكالمات ورسائل نصية
at three o'clock in the morning.
في الثالثة صباحاً.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But we are all connected to succeed,
لكن كلنا مرتبطون بالنجاح
and good leaders do this.
والقادة الناجحون يفعلون ذلك.
Tomorrow's future is sitting in our classrooms.
مستقبل الغد يجلس في قاعات الدرس،
And they are our responsibility.
وهم مسؤوليتنا.
That means everyone in here,
هذا يعني بأن كل شخص هنا ،
and those who are watching the screen.
وأولئك الذين يشاهدون الشاشة.
We must believe in their brilliance,
يجب علينا أن نؤمن بتألقهم،
and remind them by teaching them
ولنذكرهم من خلال تدريسهم
that there indeed is power in education.
بأنه بالتأكيد هنالك قوة في التعليم.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)